Brendan Shaeffer

Boston, MA | 781-879-4617 | shaefferbrendan@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

I am a fullstack developer with a passion for creative problem solving. My previous experience assisting employees exposed me to a wide variety of technical skills. As part of a team I helped spot and resolve a bug that almost caused a loss of over 200 applications. Additionally, I have entered 1,000+ individual employee training records per month. I love solving problems big and small, especially when they help make people's lives better.

TECHNICAL & INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL, Typescript

Libraries and Frameworks: React, Express.js, EJS, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Bulma

Databases and other: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful Routing, JSON API

Interpersonal skills: Communication, Empathy, Creative Problem Solving, Flexibility

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Virtual Slot Machine - GitHub | App - JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Try your luck in this virtual slot machine! The stakes are high but the rewards higher! Fully randomized outcomes with 12 unique pairings for different win amounts.

- Programmed a pseudo random number generator that checks for 12 unique win conditions within an array of random numbers.
- Designed slot wheel animations that respond dynamically to the random number system
- Integrated a confetti generator that reinforces player esteem for win conditions

EXPERIENCE

Toward Independent Living and Learning, Human Resources Assistant Dedham, MA, 05/2022 - 09/2023

- Administered and processed employee records.
- Printed 5,000+ pages monthly for new employee orientation books. Constructed books for each individual employee.
- Entered 1,000+ individual employee training records per month into the company database.
- Processed 400+ employment applications per month into the company application database. Distribute applications to relevant department leaders.
- Conducted phone screens for potential candidates. Assisted candidates through the hiring pipeline.

Dromgoole Center for Admission, Website Design Freelance

Remote, MA, 01/2021 - 02/2021

- Provided website consultation and tailored website design to client specifications.
- Implemented a website prototype using the Squarespace CMS platform with custom HTML template, and CSS styles.
- Designed a series of unique icons to represent the client's range of services offered.

United States Post Office, Processing Clerk

North Reading, MA, 04/2021 - 03/2022

- Processed varying types of mail to meet daily quotas and shipping schedules.
- As part of a team, I sorted 6,000+ individual packages weekly.
- Provided internal customer care and support as needed. Collaborated with internal customers for shipment scheduling and handling. Rapidly resolved internal customer conflicts to prevent schedule delays.

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Remote, Certificate Expected: 01/2024

Full-stack software engineering 420+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.

Rhode Island School of Design, Bachelor of Fine Arts

Providence, RI, Graduated: 05/2020